ABHISHEK SINGH RATHORE

Software Engineer

Bareilly, India | +919389732668 | abhishek.990914@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

PROFILE

Dynamic Software Developer with more than 2.5 years of experience at Mordor Intelligence. Specialized in developing high-traffic Research Development pages and boosting lead generation using EJS. Designed the Synapse and CMS-Synapse platform, including client account creation and access management modules. Demonstrates strong leadership, teamwork, adaptability, and problem-solving skills, effectively collaborating with developers at all levels on core projects.

EXPERIENCE

Mordor Intelligence - Remote

Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

- Developed high-performance, secure, and responsive RD pages for the MI official website using EJS serving approximately 50000 daily users, significantly increasing lead generation.
- Developed Companies section and Dashboards on the Synapse app, enabling clients to access Hubs and RDs based on their access level.
- Designed and implemented the architecture of the CMS-Synapse platform, including client account creation and management modules, enhancing access control and user experience.
- Developed the Lorien Frontend platform for efficient data gathering, organization, and generation of Research Documents (RDs), with export capabilities in PPT and PDF formats. Utilized Fusion Chart to create integrated graphs.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills and adaptability by collaborating with developers at all levels in an Agile
 environment to diagnose and fix bugs, address performance issues, and plan new features.

Alt Campus - Dharamshala, India

Intern Full Stack Engineer

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- Developed high-performance, responsive web applications using React.JS and Express.JS, showcasing expertise in the MERN stack.
- Deployed projects on platforms like GitHub Pages, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, and Firebase, ensuring optimal accessibility and functionality, and utilized Git for version control.

PROJECTS

Community API

 Developed an API with Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB and Mongoose, similar to Stack Overflow, ensuring proper data management and RESTful architecture.

Gemini

Built a web application similar to Gemini, using React.js and Google Generative-Al. It also has an additional feature of
object detection from videos and speech is also integrated.

Stream Sync

• Developed Stream Sync, a React.js and Node.js based video calling app with multi-party video calls, in-call chat, screen sharing, using Web Socket and Web RTC.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript | TypeScript

FRONTEND: HTML | CSS | SCSS | Next | React | Tailwind | Bootstrap | Styled Components | Ant Design | Material UI

BACKEND: Node | Express | EJS | MongoDB | Mongoose

TOOLS: Redux | RTK | Atlas | NPM | Git | Github | Bitbucket | Jira | Firebase | Vercel | Netlify | Heroku

EDUCATION

MJP Rohilkhand University - Bareilly, India

Bachelor of Technology
 2016-2020

• Percentage: 81.10

Sacred Hearts Public School - Bareilly, India

• Intermediate 2015-2016

Percentage : 81.50

J P Public School - Kashi Ram Nagar, India

High School
 2013-2014

• Percentage: 70.30

SOFT SKILLS

Problem-Solving | Communication Skills | Collaboration | Attention to details | Adaptability | Analytical Thinking

ACHIEVEMENTS

• High-Five Award for quarter of July-September 2023

High-Five Award for quarter of April-June 2023

• Extra-Miler Award for quarter of October-December 2022

• IV Position in Hackathon conducted by Github, Incubate India in June 2021